So, this might be a contrarian opinion,
but most like consumer apps that are
sort of one or two person founded
startups shouldn't raise VC. They don't
need to. I know it's a popular topic of
conversation, but I tend to think that
institutional capital is really not
designed very well for that stage.
Hello, I'm your host David Bernard. My
guest today is Greg Conn, co-founder and
CEO of Ad Hoc Labs, makers of Burner and
Dialed. On the podcast, I talk with Greg
about knowing when to pivot, why most
consumer apps shouldn't raise VC, and
why making free trials optional
outperformed making them the default.
Hey, Greg, thanks so much for joining me
on the podcast today.
>> Hey, David, great to be here. I'm
excited for this.
>> Yeah, I've been really looking forward
to this chat. you and I got a chance to
catch up in LA a few weeks ago and
talked about the business, talked about
things you're working on and as as I
often do have a conversation like that
like I got to have Greg on the podcast.
So here it is a few weeks later you're
in Austin and we get to do this in
person which is fun.
>> It works out great. If although if we
could have recorded that conversation
that would have been good too.
>> May maybe a little too deep for the
podcast but yeah it was fun. Uh I did
want to kick off talking through the
story of Ad Hoc Labs, especially I love
the early pivot and I think it's a
lesson a lot of people can learn from.
So yeah, tell tell me about the early
days of Ad Hoc Labs.
>> So my co-founder and I kind of started
with this idea that the phone app was
the crappiest app on the iPhone. Um and
it was right and we also had this sense
that you know the phone has all this
capability. It has sensors and it has,
you know, software affordances, you
know, and things like location, all all
kinds of cool things. It knows who your
friends are. It knows where you are and
where they are. But the phone itself
didn't do anything smart at all, right?
So, that was really the core insight.
And the first product we built was
called Wrangle. Like, it's a pun on
Rang, you know, without the W. And the
idea was you could find other folks who
were available for a phone call. I I
live in Los Angeles and and spend too
much time in the car and a little bit
born out of that sort of long commute
itis, right? Where you would the idea
was you would go on and see who was
available for a chat, hit a button, you
know, one tap and the phone would ring.
And when we built that, it was it was
kind of a hack on top of Twilio. So
Twilio at the time was new. We're kind
of in the 2011 time frame now, 2012. And
uh Twilio really built kind of an API
interface to a lot of telecom
complexity.
And so we were able to hit a REST API,
generate a phone number or or generate a
phone call from your phone to a phone
number and do all this sort of stuff. We
found that that particular thing was
really cool when we had a bunch of our
friends artificially using it at exactly
the same time. For an app like that to
work, you need a network, right? It's
sort of an empty restaurant problem.
Classic for social. We basically trying
to do a web 2.0 idea on top of the
phone. So that was that. um it didn't
really work well. And one of the things
that you experience when you when you
kind of have a prototype first mentality
is people are nice. So a lot of the
feedback we got was, "Oh, this is really
cool. You know who would really like
this? My sister would like this. My
girlfriend would like this.
>> She talks on the phone all the time."
And you go, "Okay, well give it to your
sister. You know, see what she thinks."
You know, and and you kind of, you know,
you're you're working uphill on these
things. And then we also had this idea
that VCs would use it as like a public
office hours,
>> right?
>> And that didn't really get any traction
either. So we came up with this hack
really on that that was designed to
kickstart that, which we called uh the
burner feature. And so in addition to
going on and seeing if you had any
friends there uh on the app, if you
didn't have any that had joined or you
had friends on the app but didn't have
any that were available, we would let
you post a phone number on Twitter or on
Facebook. Oh yeah.
>> So he hit the Twilio API, throw the
phone number on Twitter
>> cuz you wouldn't want your personal cell
phone number on Twitter obviously.
>> Definitely not.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, people did it and it was it was a
kind of a big deal like Charlie Sheen's
number got posted at one point and there
was kind of this discussion around
>> people's you know emails being on
Twitter and things like that. The way we
set it up was if you called that number,
if anyone saw that number and called it,
it would ring through to the person who
had posted it and then we would dissolve
it after 30 minutes or 60 minutes or
whatever. And that feature when we
started showing to people, they thought
it was really cool and and so they
instead of saying, you know, my sister
would use this, they would say, oh, I
want this, right? And so, um, that that
became the feature we built into burner,
right? which is to this day primarily an
app that's known as, you know, the best
and sort of most reliable place to get a
second phone number, right?
>> And that's how that evolved.
>> Well, I love that story for a few
reasons. You know, one, a lot of people
start working on things and just don't
find that pull. And so with wrangle, you
you started butdding your head up
against those like real like market
issues like, oh, somebody else will use
it and and not seeing that ground swell.
And the network effects, like you said,
it's like you pretty much need
everybody, you know, to be on there in
order for that matching to happen where
you happen to be free when somebody, you
know, happens to be free and then you
both happen to want to have a phone
call. Um, but there was like an inkling
of something. And then the second thing
I love is that you were leveraging this
new technology. So Twilio was new, phone
number as an API. And I think we're in
an age right now with AI and so many new
opportunities. You know, I mean, this is
something I do every time iOS releases a
new feature like interactive widgets.
Like my weather app uh is one of the
more um useful interactions that you can
have on the home screen. And so this
idea of like looking for opportunities
in these new spaces where this new
opportunity comes. Uh I forgot that part
of the story that that the whole genesis
of the company was like leveraging this
new technology. Um but what would you
say were the lessons and like if you
were advising somebody today they're
they're struggling to get that traction.
What are the lessons you took from that
that you would share with with folks?
>> Yeah. So one of the specific memories I
have uh of that stage we were actually
pitching Wrangler kind of in prototype
form to VCs right
>> and and you know at the time I uh had
previously worked at Yahoo for a bunch
of years and had mentored a lot of
startups in the tech stars program and
500 startups and things like that and so
we knew a lot of people. We went and met
with a lot of great you know VCs with a
reputation for supporting kind of early
stage pre-revenue type companies. We
thought, "Isn't this great? They're
going to want to fund us." And we got so
much feedback that was very,
>> well, there's something here, but it's
not quite, you know, very neutral. And
and and the learning for me on that was
first of all, consumer is hard. Yeah.
>> Right. And consumer is hard in a way
that, you know, you can take a new
technology and it absolutely creates new
opportunities to build new products. AI
is a great example of that. at the time,
you know, Twilio, before Twilio, we had,
you know, Dropbox being built on AWS.
And there's sort of many examples of
these these things that sort of build
off of a foundational technology shift.
Um, but, you know, the the sort of
market only recognizes you when you
actually have traction.
>> Yeah. And you know, that's kind of it's
a little bit of trying to catch a
falling knife, I think, to try to get
into the seed round or the A round or
whatever of a of a consumer startup
after the growth potential has been sort
of validated. Right.
>> Right. And so we were pre that
validation and we were chasing it. And
knowing what I know today, I would look
at that strictly as a distribution
problem.
>> Right. And I think,
>> well, was it just a distribution problem
or was it a product problem? Because I
mean those are the two main things,
right? Is the product not pulling?
>> Yeah.
>> Or like would wrangle have worked if you
could have figured out distribution or
was wrangle just not the product.
>> So I think we did not really know how to
build at that time like a viral loop
where where it was self-perpetuating.
>> That was really early, right? That was
2012.
>> That was 20 late 2011 I think. Yeah,
maybe early 2012. It's interesting
because there there are apps, there are
founders out there, there are founding
teams out there that are very adept at
kind of generating attention and an
early audience. And and today, of
course, you know, we have, you know, Tik
Tok and kind of all these other sort of
new new influencer vectors relative to
what might have been available even been
five years ago. And with Wrangle, you
know, if we had a large audience trying
it out from some kind of media
validation like that, that would have
been fine. Or if we had, you know, every
user invites three friends,
>> a factor driven growth,
>> right?
>> Um, that might have worked. That wasn't
really necessarily our strength. And,
>> um, in the end, you know, Burner, which
is what it became,
>> is pretty much a single player app.
Right.
>> Right. We've never really had a network
effect model on that versus a lot of
other messaging apps that are
fundamentally, you know, WhatsApp is is
the ultimate example of of kind of a
network effect messaging app. Right. I
do think it would have worked well if we
had a lot of users to start out.
>> Right.
>> Right. And ultimately, in fact, there
are other apps that had very similar
ideas and and and were successful.
>> Okay. But um WhatsApp was actually
started on on the idea of what that
that's called presence but who's
available thing and Slack has you know
>> kind of a
>> being online
>> peer-to-p peer messaging you know
availability is is the feature right
>> so so for a team that's struggling how
how would you think about whether it is
a product problem you need to pivot to a
new product because for you I mean maybe
that was a blessing in disguise because
maybe wrangle could have seen a certain
amount of success but then would have
hit a wall but instead it kind of forced
a pivot because you didn't have the
distribution and you landed on what was
actually a better product that then had
kind of pull in the market. So how would
you advise people to think about when is
it a distribution problem where you just
can't find the eyeballs and when is it a
product problem that you're you don't
have a level of product market fit
that's worth investing in.
>> Yeah. Um, I would back into that, you
know, by thinking a little bit about
retention. And I think there's a
fundamental thing there, which is to
say, well, what problem does it solve?
And I think the learning with wrangle
ultimately was it didn't solve a real
problem,
>> right? People weren't necessarily
looking for kind of another way to get
get more phone calls. Yeah.
>> You know what I mean? It was a problem
for me, right?
>> I was stuck in a car commuting from
Santa Monica or whatever, you know?
Well, and maybe you're the extrovert who
actually wanted to call [laughter]
I enjoy my podcast when I have a long
drive.
>> For sure. You know, it's fun, but you
know, and and also in the in the era of
mobile phones, you know, if you're in
the car and you've got an hour to kill,
you're driving to the airport or
something, you start calling people,
they're all you're just getting their
voicemail, they're all screening you,
you don't know whether to leave a
message, you know, they they start
calling you back. It's it's a messy
problem, but it really wasn't a problem
that people were going to look for an
app to solve or looking for kind of an
extraneous tool for. And when we sort of
pivoted into the burner standalone app
where you know we had built that feature
and that feature was generating positive
results and then we were doing stuff
like testing it by selling tickets on
Craigslist and we were posting fake ads
for giving away flat screen TVs and
things like that. We just get you know a
ton of traffic and it was what that did
was it quickly validated the problem.
>> Right.
>> Right. And so
>> started to feel pull from the market
instead of having to push yourself into
the market.
>> That's exactly right. And and it was
like a 10x to 100x level of response
from even just friends we were showing
this to. So in that actual stage, we
went down to South by Southwest here in
Austin 2012, right?
>> And we it wasn't sort of hardened and
ready. It wasn't in the app store or
anything like that, but we were showing
it to friends on test flight and people,
you know, we ended up like with the New
York Times interview and we ran back to
our room and we kind of set up a warm
room and set up a like a launch page,
you know, we were capt capturing uh
waiting lists,
>> names, and you know, we were on a panel,
you know, it was just like it happened
really fast and it for us it was a real
sign that there was something here that
was actually meaningful sort of an
authentic problem
>> they were solving for people and and you
know as much as has happened since then
there's you know a lot of evolution we
can we can get into around our product
and around how we've thought about
growth and things like that fundamental
piece has has really only deepened
>> right having only one phone number
associated with your mobile phone is
even more of a problem today
>> you know for even more reasons right and
more use cases than it was when we
started burner.
>> Yeah, that's cool though that I mean and
that this is what you want to see in a
product is getting that pull. Now you're
you know very few people are going to
get to have that experience of being at
South by Southwest and New York Times
interviews and stuff like that. But I
think you know for a product to succeed
if you're pushing pushing pushing and
you're not getting any kind of a
flywheel people aren't excited about it
you know maybe that's a good sign that
it is time to pivot and it is the
product you know if you've if you
haven't if you're not good at
distribution but you're at least trying
and you're not getting any pull then
maybe it is time to look at at pivot. I
I think there's, you know, too many
people work for too long on products
that just don't solve a real problem
that don't don't fill a need that or
fill a need that such a small number of
people have. And I mean today, you know,
if you're an indie developer and you're
you're you that extrovert and you want
to have phone calls and maybe there is a
small market of people, but you're not
going to build a venture scale business.
You're not going to build a big business
solving those little tiny problems that
not many people have. Uh but it's
fascinating to hear that that and and
once you start building though you start
seeing things you start seeing like oh
this there's an inkling of something
here there's and and then again with the
like Twilio API opportunity you were
experimenting in a place that led you
somewhere and you were able to pivot
into something bigger. So I I think it's
just a fun story for people to listen to
to learn from. But I did want to go back
and talk about at what point did you
decide to raise money and why in that
journey? Did did you raise it before
that that that blow up at South by
Southwest or did you raise after on the
kind of heels of that?
>> So we were raising during that. It was
actually like I got my first commitment
um on the bus to the Salt Lake that uh
that uh First Round Capital would run
these buses out to to the Salt Lake. But
actually it was Dave Mccclure from 500
Startups and I and I pinned him into a
seat and made him listen to my pitch.
Um, and then uh David Cohen from from
Tech Stars, the founder of Tech Stars on
the same day at a different at a
different event, you know, he committed,
but uh you know, neither of those guys
is a fool and wanted to be the only
money in. And so I had to I had a
target. I think I was trying to raise a
half a million and I didn't quite get
there. And so we actually never closed
um before launching. We we launched the
app, you know, kind of on my credit card
um in terms of the Twilio account,
right? And um and in fact that informed
the pricing model because the phone
numbers cost money.
>> So we believe it or not, Burner was a
paid download when it first launched.
$1.99 to download it.
>> Wow.
>> And then it it included a free phone
number for 7 days or something and then
you could re-up it kind of like credits,
right?
>> It had this credit system. It was kind
of elaborate thing. you could buy, you
know, 3, eight, you know, 15 or 25
credits for different price points and
and then different configurations of
phone numbers to extend them. Um, but
when that's what it was when we launched
it and we priced it out so that we would
basically if a user used every bit of
what they were allocated in terms of
texts and call minutes
>> that we would and after Apple got their
cut, we would we would break exactly
even on the Toyota cost. And then
anything that a user didn't use was
profit basically. So any breakage was
profit. Um and when we launched, we had
like $50,000 in revenue on the first
day, right? So we just got picked up. It
was it was uh I think Gigahome that
covered us and we were on
>> Hacker News as a top story. It was
generating debate and it kind of you
know you can't recreate that today. like
you said, it's not South by Southwest in
2012, but but analoges of that exist
today on on Tik Tok and Instagram and
anyone can go viral for a feature,
right? And so we kind of had a little
moment where we had initial
>> traction and at that point a couple of
months had gone by since those early
commitments and everything closed within
a couple weeks of that moment and it was
like, okay,
>> did you raise the price?
>> Yeah. Well, things changed a little bit
and you know, the product had changed
completely. We were raising on initially
kind of a concept version of Wrangle
with this burner thing as a kind of a
little by catch on it,
>> right?
>> And then and then it became burner
became, you know, we had to redo the
deck and all that stuff. But it was I do
think, you know, it was maybe more
driven by signals that there was a
consumer app here that had resonance,
>> right?
>> Um, and you know, we didn't invent the
category of of the second phone number.
you know, Google Voice predated us by a
number of years. It's a free product.
Skype had sort of a variation of this
and and what we did do was we reinvented
it for mobile
>> and we made it, you know, much more
oriented to the privacy control oriented
consumer and the UX was just I think 10x
better. Not that I'm biased, you know,
it would it was better enough to
generate a lot of interest and and and
people willing to pay us
>> kind of a classic painkiller, not a
vitamin. Right.
>> Right.
>> So, um, at that point, I think, yeah,
you know, we we raised an angel round.
The thing we wanted to do was take the
paid download
off, right? Became a free download. We
figured out the conversion math
>> and then we also launched an Android in
that sort of next six or eight months.
And then we actually subsequently raised
a VC round which is its own sort of set
of set of things and dynamics. But um
again I think that was very driven by
those early signals and and and coming
back to your comment about pivoting or
understanding when you have that you
know one of the signals you can start to
see once you have a little bit of
traction of course is is retention
>> right? And so not just sort of revenue
retention, but there's any number of
ways you can look at how many, you know,
what's your DAU to MAU ratio and how
often are people coming back and using
an app or what what hooks can you kind
of um evolve to to re-engage people. And
>> yeah,
>> one of the things I call it is a pre
premium feature user retention. Is the
thing you're going to sell something
that people keep using? Right. Right.
And so if your subscription if your if
your payw wall has locked a feature,
well a hard payw wall would lock all
features. So any feature would be
premium user retention, premium feature
user retention. But yeah, are people
coming back to that thing that you think
is the hook that is the valuable thing
in the app.
>> I actually think this is a really hard
problem. So we're we're you know 10
years later, right? We have a lot of
features. Some of those are are locked
behind. We have multiple tiers of
subscriptions including a standard and a
premium today.
>> And the discussion of whether something
should be included in the premium bundle
or you know used to drive engagement at
the free tier or the standard tier I
think it's it's not always obvious.
>> No, it's not.
>> But but having that signal of people
coming back to it is is key. You can
make a lot of money with a gimmick like
the $9.99 download. I mean, the Ibeer
app, you know, this is a famous example
of that. 99 cents, you pretend you're
drinking a beer.
>> I love that the era of the app store, by
the way, the flashlights.
>> It was great. But you're not building a
real business. You're making I mean,
whatever that guy made like, you know,
hundreds of thousands or a million
dollars, but it's a flash in the pan
because it's not something that people
come back to and they're not pretending
to drink a beer on a weekly or monthly
or even annual basis. You do it a few
times. It's a funny party gag. And and
that's where the paid up front actually
made a lot of sense for those kind of
apps where today I think you do see a
lot of people with that kind of app
charging via subscription but they don't
have any retention because you're not
going to keep doing that thing and so
it's kind of more flash in the pan and
you're you're and so I mean you know
more power to you if you can capitalize
on those kind of moments and that kind
of attention. Um but that's very
different than trying to build a real
business. So I wanted to get back to the
the raising BC. What was your thought
process in raising at that time
>> and then kind of how do you think about
advising folks especially today in the
mobile space
>> when whether or not to raise and how to
think about raising?
>> Yeah, sure. So, this might be a
contrarian opinion but I I would posit
that most apps and especially most like
consumer apps that are sort of one or
two person founded startups shouldn't
raise VC. They don't need to. Um I know
it's a popular topic of conversation but
um I tend to think that institutional
capital is really not designed very well
for that stage uh for particularly I
mean we were talking about some of the
flashlight apps and some of the more I
don't want to I don't want to say
gimmicky
>> in the sense that sometimes these things
can start with a small insight and and
get traction that may be ultimately a
meaningful insight not just a gimmick,
but I don't think that necessarily
follows that it's a good idea to raise,
you know, real VC, which, you know, is
driven by VC math, right? Which is
driven by the idea that that any one
investment could potentially repay sort
of an entire fund, right?
>> Right. in terms of returns. Um, it's
actually pretty hard to do that when and
when you start doing the math, you know,
you have to have these hundreds of
millions or billions of dollars of
outcomes at the end in order to make
that work. And that's actually even more
true today than it was then. And then I
think you cross that with consumer,
right? And and you're kind of really
working on early signals. At the time we
we were a little bit innocent and it was
a different time in terms of you know
you could still get press
you know that was there's an app for
that essentially and you know we thought
we could potentially build a very big
consumer scale business here. We have
built a very scaled business.
>> I was going to say
>> um but but it's not a a billion dollar
valuation scale business today. I mean
we're we're on track you know for for a
large scale business but it's taken a
long time
>> so speed of return matters and um you
know we've built a very authentic
durable business but we've kind of done
that in some ways despite having raised
VC
>> right
>> and we've had very supportive investors
but I think we got very lucky with that
for most founders I would say my advice
generally is don't raise VC because you
and raise VC because you feel like you
have to,
>> right?
>> Or you really want to and kind of you
understand what's behind that.
>> Yeah. And then maybe adding on to that,
make sure you raise from the right folks
that if it doesn't turn out to be a
venture scale business, they're not
going to sell it for parts, put too much
pressure on you, run the business into
the ground, or any other number of
things that some VCs will do in that
situation.
>> Choosing your partners carefully
absolutely goes without saying. I mean,
and and there's there's lots of advice
out there on this. It is ultimately a
fairly rare situation where the founder
has like so many different offers of
funding that they get to pick. And so,
so a lot of times, you know, a founder
is faced with a choice or founding team
is faced with a choice of here's
somebody who wants to invest in me. They
want to put, you know, $500,000 or, you
know, $1.5 million into my company and
and they're kind of setting the terms
and you have to say yes or no, right?
And so I just think it's really
important to understand what's behind
that.
>> You just said earlier that you know when
you were launching Burner the Twilio
account was on your personal credit
card. So how do how do you recommend
folks navigate those early stages where
a little bit of money would help? I mean
this is something I hear all the time.
It's like gosh if I just had you know 20
50k to kickstart UA or to at least try
or I need money for this or that. I
think that's that's why people I think
idealize raising VC is that oh if I just
had more money would solve the problem.
So how do you get through those early
stages without any help?
>> Yeah. Well the classic 3Fs friends,
family and fools is probably the right
source of capital
>> right
>> for you know that sort of early I want
to throw a few ads on on Facebook or
something and test it with some users.
You know 20K can go a long way. you
can't really sort of quit your day job
and and pay multiple salaries and, you
know, kind of have enough money in the
bank to just go design apps if you never
never done this before, you know, at
least not reliably, right? That that's a
big sort of bet. But if you
>> are scrappy and you're, you know, able
to be personally sort of low burn,
whatever your personal circumstances
are, you know, and you just need a
little bit of money, you should not be
even thinking about institutional
capital. If you start to have some early
validation, you start to get maybe a
wider set of options and you can start
to think about things like the Y
cominator program or other programs like
Techars that do put some cash in but do
so on fairly open-ended governance.
>> Right? So there's this whole stage or um
kind of model around safes and
convertible notes and things like that
that they sort of set you on a path
toward venture capital, but they don't
absolutely lock you in if something goes
sideways.
>> And we were in that stage for a while
and that and that, you know, kind of
ultimately it worked out really well for
us. The way we did it, we have um a VC
who's just very aligned to early stage
uh founderled companies, founder
collective, and they've been very
supportive as things have evolved kind
of off the classic
>> alphabet series of rounds one after
another. Um and it's nice not to have to
go raise more money in order to survive
as a company, right? But if you're
trying to compete in a large category or
in a SAS business or something like
that, you kind of have to do that. And
that's when VC is maybe the right
choice,
>> right? This will be a much smaller
audience, but I think even those who
aren't in this situation would be
curious and will learn something. What
was that transition like? And what was
the time span from we're raising VC,
we're going to be a billion dollar
outcome to okay, maybe we're not and
let's not raise more and let's, you
know, shift to a slower growth
profitable mindset.
>> Yeah. So, we closed our angel round
right after that sort of first launch
and we raised about a $2 million VC
round within a year or so of that.
That's the one I'm referring to. And it
was with that that you know the job of a
round right from a sort of classic point
of view is to prove something or
validate something. And so we were
trying to go out and use that really
you're buying time
>> and you're buying time to validate a
market and we were trying to figure out
you know how big this market might be.
After a period of time, you know, we
were starting to run low on that cash
and we had tried a lot of experiments
including trying to make a premium
business out of burner very much has a
similar formula today as it did back
then. It's it's it's evolved in a lot of
meaningful ways, but at its core, it
does one thing really well, right, which
is download app, get phone number,
>> right?
>> Okay. And those phone numbers cost
money.
>> Yeah. So you can't just give it away to
a million people
>> and hope you know 1% of them convert
after some number of months, right? You
have to figure out a way to make that a
or well you can do that with a lot of
capital.
>> So we tested some things like that to
see would it make sense to raise more
capital and do more of that. There were
some other ad supported competitors kind
of in the market emerging around the
same time we did and we were looking at
those and trying to do the analytics on
what they were doing and we saw
potential to have kind of a business
that was a mile wide and an inch deep
but we weren't sure how it would get to
be really valuable down that path and
what we were seeing in our business we
were from the beginning revenue driven
kind of a premium app like a good
experience we're investing a thought in
the craft of what we were building and
trying to use technology creatively to
give people a good experience and then
charge for it,
>> right?
>> And people were paying add a new
subscription tier or add a new higher
price point and people would some people
would buy it, right? And renew. And so
it it became clear somewhere in there
that this was going to be a nice, you
know, healthy business and grow at a
certain rate, but it wasn't going to be,
you know, kind of 200% growth
year-over-year and and and scale in that
way, at least not in any way that we had
unlocked. And so, you know, there was a
period of time where we considered going
out for more money that it was on the
timeline. It was time to go raise a
series A. it was clear we didn't have
the metrics for it,
>> right? And so that's the ultimate test
of whether you should raise VC today is
at the end of that cycle will you have
the numbers to go raise a subsequent
round
>> and we didn't get there. So we had some
insider support to kind of convert the
business into a break even at the time
business and we've been really
profitable ever since. So, for six or
eight years, we've been, you know,
either break even or or meaningfully
profitable and and while still also
growing the top line,
>> which is great. It's it's a and it's a
>> I mean, that's ultimately what you're
trying to build toward. And so, you just
got there quicker, but then grew slower,
but you started with profit, which is
great.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, just to give you
some numbers, right? So, I think we had
our first million annual year at about
two and a half years in and then, you
know, we had a $5 million year by about
five years in and, you know, it took
another couple years to get to 10
million and now we're we're multiples of
that today.
>> But it, you know, this is when when I
see the dialogue out there about
founders flipping apps for 100K or
something like that, I think, well, if
you have something
>> Yeah. you know, build it,
>> right? And uh if you don't have
anything, who wants to buy it,
>> right? And so there's sort of a
>> my advice would be if you, you know, can
can find the authenticity or the real
problem within the thing you're getting
traction on, then that's an interesting
thing to keep exploring further.
>> Yeah.
>> And at some point capital becomes an
issue, right? If you kind of saying
you're in a situation where it's
growing, you're retaining and you need
you know help whether that's to do user
acquisition and you you are in a
position to increase your your budgets
or you know product evolution then you
have an interesting problem right and I
do see a lot of apps out there sort of
in the let's say sub 5 million in
revenue who you know they're maybe not
going to raise VC they're not growing at
a rocket ship sort of explosive type of
rate but it's a real business and they
need capital and so what do they do?
>> The capital markets aren't well set up
for that. I don't think
>> today we look more like a growth stage
business or maybe a PE business,
>> right? Not a venture business, but those
kinds of investors aren't interested in
really small to them. Really small is
very large to lots of lots of founders.
But um it's an interesting tweeter kind
of problem I think.
>> Yeah. And there and there are options
now surfacing in the market. you know,
Bravo, Pollen VC, there's others who are
kind of filling this gap for that level
of company. And then, you know, revenue
cap, we're launching a product soon for
that factoring where you can get the
revenue ahead from when Apple pays, so
you can accelerate a little faster.
There there's little bits and pieces of
options for apps today to to get some of
that, but it's just it's not like a big,
you know, $2 million series A influx of
cash. you you know I I think somebody
anybody who's innovating in the sort of
financial space serving founders like
that that's fantastic right so that just
creates more options for founders
sometimes you know they're not the right
price for founders or whatever but at
least they they have those options and
and they exist but you know as a as a
founder of a of an app you don't also
want to be kind of trying to innovate on
the finance side you just want to you
know take something off the shelf and
and you may not be familiar with some of
these things.
>> Yeah. Well, I wanted to go back in the
story again and talk about the credit
system and kind of the transition from
credits to subscription and where all
that landed because it's kind of funny.
I I've talked a lot on the podcast about
how, you know, if you are a subscription
app and it was actually just the most
recent podcast was Revy Ravi Meta who
worked at Tinder and looking at the
demand curve and fitting those
consumable credit kind of economy on top
of the subscriptions, but you went the
opposite way. Yeah. So early on in
Burner, you had a credit system and then
layered on subscriptions and the
subscriptions were the unlock for you,
not the credit system. So I I kind of
swed your thunder a little, but like
tell me how all that went.
>> In a funny way, by the way, we ended up
in the same place, right? So today we
have a business that's more than 90%
subscription revenue and the the 10% or
you know 8% or whatever that's that's
credits is mostly existing subscribers
topping up, not people who are avoiding
the the subscription system. Right? So
we we kind of evolved to that, but we
started off um as you know credits were
something you could purchase in an inapp
purchase, right? And they were
ultimately kind of a consumable. You
would use them to get uh extend a phone
number or get an additional phone
number. And one of the differentiators
of burner is you could have multiple
phone numbers, right? So you could have
three, four phone numbers. I actually
think the right number of phone numbers
for most people is not is not two. It's
not like your main line and your burner
line. having a couple of burners, right?
So you can keep one for, you know, your
long-term sort of podcasts and and use
one for spam or special circumstances
like shopping for a car and so on,
right? And so we had this model that
people could kind of mix and match and
some of them didn't even have, you know,
the capability to send pictures,
>> MMS, right? And so we thought, okay, and
and in the back of our mind, we were
looking at games and apps like Zingga,
you know, that were kind of gifying
inapp purchases a little bit, like a
poker chip mentality. Yeah. So you buy
the credits and then,
>> you know, we had this vision where in
addition to phone numbers, we'd have,
you know, maybe vanity area codes or
special features, ringtones or
something. You know, we never really did
any of that, but it it worked out pretty
well. And when the AP subscription
capability rolled out, we got pretty
excited about that and looked for the
right product fit to that, right? So, it
was very important to us that it wasn't
just, well, here's a way we could make
money. And and a lot of our thinking
about growth, by the way, and features
is driven by trying to fit an offering
to an authentic need or an unmet need
among our users. And in this case,
people wanted to keep their burners,
>> right? They wanted to not accidentally
lose them.
>> Yeah.
>> There's some set of users to this day
that come through, they need a phone
number for a specific purpose. A lot of
our users have very high intent, but
sometimes that intent is is shortlived,
right? So,
>> you're you're selling a bunch of stuff
on Craigslist.
>> You can have a great experience with a
one month uh kind of tenure as a paying
customer.
>> Yeah. And many of those users kind of
come back later, but there's a lot of
users who want them for a long long or
indefinite period of time.
>> Funny enough, I I am that user. Um, I
don't use burner because I got mine
pre-burner. I got a freaking Skype
number in 2008 for my business because I
wanted a business number and I didn't
want my business number to be my
personal cell phone number. And so I've
paid Skype I don't know how many
hundreds of dollars over the last 18
years I've been running my business. And
it was I was exactly that use case. And
so it makes sense that shift to
subscription for people like me who have
this long-term need to maintain a phone
number.
>> And it's very sticky especially if you
don't use that number all the time. You
probably have it on some filings and
forms and your post office box and
>> you know if you delete it you you miss
the renewal notice and so on. those. In
fact, my I have a lot of burners, as you
might guess. I have a lot of phone
numbers. In fact, maybe I'll put one in
the show notes for people to reach out
um if they want to. But the one that is
the the one I the last one I will give
up,
>> right,
>> is the one I almost never use,
>> right? It's the one that's on, you know,
kind of long-term things like that. And
so when we went out with the first
subscription offering, it was really
driven around meeting, you know, a
segment of our users needs who wanted to
keep their number for longer. Um, and we
wanted to make that a fully featured
thing. So there was a lot of backstage
work to get MMS, which at that time
wasn't something that was supported by
the carriers through aggregators like
Twilio. Google Voice didn't have it,
right? And so, you know, nobody had it.
We were I think the first to get it out
there commercially and we rolled it into
our first subscription offering. So it
was a pretty big moment and it was a
huge success for us. So that was one of
the biggest singlestep functions in our
revenue growth in our history was the
day we launched subscriptions.
>> Um and it was also our first unlimited
all you can eat. You know, you can have
an unlimited number of texts and and
voice minutes and and photo messages. So
it wasn't it wasn't kind of counted.
>> Yeah. And that involved contractual
negotiation and other things with our
suppliers, right? It got a little bit
complex to build as a product, but then
was really successful as a as a um skew
bundle. And then immediately we
>> started to say, okay, well, what
percentage of people are taking the
monthly and the annual? What's the
retention of monthly? And you know,
completely change the the game in terms
of cohort math,
>> right?
I would say today, you know, we know as
much or more about cohort subscription
cohort math as anybody. And it's like a
really important dimension of our
business and growth. But at that time,
that was just like the beginning of
learning about all of that. That was I
think our first subscription offering we
had monthly and annual. That was it. And
now we today we have monthly oneline,
monthly threeline, annual of both of
those. And then we have that standard
and premium. So that's that's eight cues
right there. And then we have the
credits for buying up on top of that.
But we did sort of slowly deprecate
credits on the back of launching
subscriptions. Um because our our
mindset at least originally was well we
should move all of our users through a
subscription model and the ones who have
longerterm intent will retain and the
ones who who don't will will leave
early. Um and so as a consequence of
that we have reasonably high churn. And
I look back at that decision and I go,
well, we might have been able to fit to
the curve even more efficiently if we
had maintained a more front and center
credits model for those lower those
users with lower long-term intent but
high short-term intent. So, you know,
we're constantly reooking at that and
testing things and you never know that
may resurface at some point.
>> Yeah. No, it's fascinating and uh it's
fascinating too that and I I didn't know
this about Tinder, but talking to Robbie
uh in the last episode, he said, you
know, as with you, most of the inapp
purchase revenue is from subscribers
because it's a force multiplier of the
subscription. It's not as much a
standalone, but I think it can be all
things. And so for you right now it is
mostly subscribers but maybe there is an
opportunity for non-subscriber and to
add more on top of the subscription to
continue like you said to fit the fit
that demand curve.
>> I think um products change over time in
the context of their marketplace as well
>> and so one of the contexts that is very
important to us is in general the
telecom landscape. This is maybe not
super relevant to a large subset of your
users, but it's if you if you sort of
abstract that, right, the the the things
that we're trying to accomplish are not
necessarily well served by having tons
and tons of users with really short-term
>> phone numbers that are that are kind of
effectively hard to distinguish from
from spammy behavior if telecom
ecosystem. and and we think of that as
kind of a a buildup of an an increase in
the kind of quality of our users over
time as well.
>> Implicit in what you just said and
something you seem to have been very
focused on over time is that kind of
ethical perspective and we we've kind of
like hinted at it a few times here of
the you know pump and dump and gimmicks
and things like that. But I I read a
story and I wanted to hear a little bit
more about this opportunity you had
where you saw that users were using
Burner to game the Uber uh referral
program to get a bunch of money, but you
chose not to leverage that in marketing.
What what's like your ethical framework
for how you run the business and and why
do you think that's important?
>> Yeah, and I think that that's a good
example, but there are there are lots of
examples, right? I mean the phone number
industry is full of sort of I don't want
to call them scammy opportunities but
but it's it's kind of attracts a lot of
hustle culture type of people and you
know that was a great example of that.
So there was this moment in time where
Uber in its early days had a referral
program that could earn you free rides
and credits on Uber if you would
introduce friends and and we actually
got a call from Uber. I don't that's how
we knew about it. I don't know if I put
that in the article. Somebody at Uber's
growth team called us and we had, you
know, shared VCs and stuff and and I
thought, "Oh man, we're, you know,
they're going to hammer us in this." And
they were actually really excited. They
were like, "This is great." You know,
people are, you know, it's there's some
obviously, you know, kind of inauthentic
aspect of it. But there were also a lot
of people that were signing up for Uber
accounts that didn't want to put their
real phone number in Uber because they
were afraid drivers would call them,
>> right? And today Uber has this you know
sort of well architected system that
anonymizes phone numbers but they didn't
have that sort of as fully baked in the
early days. I think it worked very
lightly in certain situations but
a thing would happen where a user would
leave something in a car and and you
know the the driver could no longer call
the user and vice versa. And so people
were using burners for all kinds of
things in the Uber ecosystem. Um, and
the growth team was like, we're happy to
have this. We just want to understand
how it's working. But in our end, we
didn't want to promote, you know, hey,
get burners and you can get, you know,
extra Uber accounts and go get extra
referral credits and promote the idea
that, you know, a phone number is a way
to sort of hack the system, right? the
authentic thing that that burner solves
and and this is this is kind of almost a
like a guiding story for us is I I this
is something I say internally all the
time which is like to to team members if
you're stuck in an elevator with the CEO
of a wireless company. you know, Verizon
Wireless's CEO is in the elevator with
you. What is your sort of 30 secondond
pitch on on why Burner exists in a world
that has, you know, cell phones
everywhere? And, you know, the very
short version of that is people really
want to use phone numbers for many
things. And those things have a lot of
value to them. And even if it's your
texting to make a dentist appointment or
you're getting alerts about your flight
being delayed, that that is really
important. You just don't want all of
that on your main private personal cell
phone number. And so it's a kind of on
the one hand a service to users to have
mobile phones everywhere, but a
tremendous disservice to users to make
them do it all on one phone number.
>> Yeah.
>> And so that that's a problem we
authentically solve for people. Like we
help with that and that's the message we
want people to understand about our
product. By the way, we do a lot of
other things too. We have a VPN and we
have spam blocking and we have AI
voicemail handling. We have all these
features that we we've evolved over the
years into helping people control how
their data kind of is used on the
internet and how people reach them. But
um you know in terms of those individual
use cases that might generate a few
press hits.
>> Yeah.
>> You know that's sort of less an
important part of of our value
proposition than helping people
understand okay this is my phone number
is my identity. this is what I'm signing
in with and I'm registering at the bank
with. How can I, you know, just get a
little more control over that in a more
authentic way?
>> Yeah. I mean, just just again, the
thread through this conversation is that
in trying to build a long-term
profitable real business, not
associating yourself with hacks and
scams. It's like, yeah, you may have
seen a revenue bump from promoting that
people could gain the Uber credit system
to make, you know, you would have you
would have seen a bump and you would
have made some money, but you chose not
to see that bump and make that money
with that long-term vision. And so I
know you advise a lot of founders like
how do you advise that kind of hustle
culture startup person who would
otherwise want to take advantage of
something like that but maybe it is a
very short-term thing that handicaps
them in the long run.
>> I met a founder not too long ago and he
showed me a feature that had kind of
gotten some vir I'm not going to name it
but he' kind of gotten some virality
from this feature. It wasn't in any way
a scam. It was a very legitimate thing.
It it had sort of escaped the event
horizon on on Tik Tok and and Instagram.
And he showed it to me and I thought,
"Oh, that's brilliant." You know,
>> and and how's that feature doing? And he
said, "I designed it to go viral. I
don't really necessarily care if people
use it, and I don't think a lot of
people really do, you know, I thought,
okay, so in no way is that a scam,
right?"
>> Right. But it sort of
>> it was a good attention getter. You know
what I mean? And then I think in this
particular case, the app is fairly
sticky once you get in there. And so I
think there was more sort of meat on the
bone there than just the the throwaway
feature. But it was a really interesting
version of that, right? Where I think
you can do a lot of things to get
attention. And you have to do some of
that. You can't just sit around and
>> and product your way to glory, right?
You have to find a way to break out, get
attention, do things. And so I just
think, you know, from early on we've had
many opportunities to take a high road
or a low road, you know, and there's
there's a lot of low road tactics out
there or just kind of lowest common
denominator tactics that a good example
of that is clones, right? There's
>> we've been cloned a bunch of times, a
bunch of crappy,
>> you know, fake burner apps out there.
Um, we've had opportunities to clone
features or or emulate, you know, other
apps that have that have been successful
and we we choose to do things kind of
the way we develop them independently.
>> And that's I think that's speaks to who
we are, not just like
>> Yeah.
>> kind of something that's written above
the door.
>> Yeah. And it speaks to building toward a
billion dollar outcome versus flash in
the pan or or being associated Yeah.
being associated with the with stuff you
don't want to be associated with as a as
a brand, as a business, and everything
else.
>> Well, and a billion dollar outcome is
that feels like a huge sort of
large and unapproachable target for all
but a few apps out there, right? But to
say, you know, $100 million in revenue
if you're already at tens of millions is
it's linear, right? It's very
achievable. Yeah. And 10 million is very
achievable if you're at 1 million and
and you know fractally all the way down,
right? Like you can really build a real
business. It just takes a long time and
there's a lot of um in in in our case we
think of it as a lot of operational
discipline and and a lot of you know
sort of thoughtful process around what
we're good at all the way through the
funnel, right? And so like I think the
conversations about raising money, you
know, those are premature if you don't
have the fundamentals of the business.
>> Yeah.
>> Just as a side note, I used to be in
book publishing. I was an editor uh at a
a trade publishing house called St.
Martins's Press before I moved into
tech. And at cocktail parties, people
would always approach me about how to
get their their book read or their book
published, you know, or how to get an
agent or how to get an editor. And the
answer was always, well, do you have a
book,
>> right?
>> Most of the time the answer was no,
right? So, it's like, well, write a good
book, start there, you know, and build
on that.
>> Build a good product and go from there.
It doesn't have to be, you know, deep
and fully featured, but, you know,
something that that works. You know, you
can really have a single serving product
and then and then build on it
substantially.
>> Yeah. Well, I wanted to dive into some
more tactical things. I know as a
company over time, you've done a ton of
experiments. Uh so any in the progress
that you've made from going from that
million to the five to now tens of
millions of dollars of revenue, what
were some of the key learnings along the
way and the process for obtaining those
learnings?
>> Yeah. Um I you know one thing that I
think uh is really important is to focus
on analytics as early as you can. um we
set out from day one to be a datadriven
company and by the way to be a very
engineering and productdriven company
not just a product driven company right
and I think there's a lot of overlap
there in in analytics as you start to
stitch together data that's coming from
the product itself you know in the
client things that are coming from the
server analytics things that are coming
from the marketing analytics and and how
you munchge those together and all that
really starting to understand cohort
math um and understanding
you know you can run an experiment and
the experiment throws data but how do
you pick the winner right unless you
kind of know what you're trying to
actually optimize for I would say you
know where we have done I think an
exceptional job is fairly high in the
funnel we have you know done over the
years I mentioned some of our SKUs you
know within that there's what's in and
what's out of each bundle. There's
pricing. There's, you know, kind of
what's the default, right? There's a lot
of sort of opportunity to experiment
and and explore, you know, also, of
course, the design and the positioning,
right? And that's also true in our UA,
right? We we have a pretty robust user
acquisition program and a lot of a lot
of creative variance and a lot, you
know, there's sort of a lot there,
right? And so, um, what's what's been
interestingly
true for us consistently, I'll come back
to experiments in a minute, but you
know, what we don't do as a company is a
whole lot of brand marketing,
>> right?
>> We have a great brand, by the way. I I
like to say,
>> I love burner.
>> Thank you. I I like to say it passes the
F1 sort of car test.
>> Like, you could you can imagine it,
right? But but if we ran, you know,
>> if somebody gave us $10 million and we
ran a Super Bowl ad, you know, that's
not necessarily a very targeted audience
for us.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and when we have had some like
breakout mainstream press, you know,
every now and again we've been covered
in like Vogue or something, you know,
and and people come download the app,
but those people don't convert and they
don't retain,
>> right? So, so the thing that's been true
is we've we've been pretty focused on
there's a lot of natural intent that
already exists for our app,
>> right? For for burner. People go into
the app store, people go on to search
engines and search for second phone
number, temporary phone number, private
phone number, burner app, you know, by
brand. And um we're very good at finding
that and harvesting that in terms of
getting people to download the app. And
then so we're working with a pretty high
um intent audience and then so that
gives us a lot of like surface area to
test different pay walls um and
different you know things at that
onboarding funnel right so that's
I think incredibly important um and the
for a long time has been the biggest
single factor in our retention right
which is like well what did we what did
we sell them into
>> right
>> is kind of the biggest determinant of
what their trajectory is as a customer.
Um, and what we've been building on is
our ability then to retain them, right?
Um, and you know, give customers more
value, kind of stickier features, things
that address maybe things they had less
intent about as they came in. Right? So,
I mean, there any number of features
we've launched, but I'll mention one
that was a surprise to me. Um, we have
in our premium tier, we have the ability
if someone calls you on your burner and
you don't recognize the phone number to
do kind of a lookup through the telefan
system of of, you know, and make a
pretty good guess of who that that is,
who that caller is. And that feature has
been very popular. Um, it's funny
because when people get burners, they
think they're being they think we're
selling their numbers. Sometimes we get
these comments like, "Oh, I started
getting all these telemarketing calls."
like not we're not the ones selling 100%
I can definitively state we are not but
>> but that's the whole point of getting a
burner is as soon as you give your phone
number out once it's
>> it's out and then people realize when
they would they use this lookup feature
oh actually this is somebody you know
calling me um so that's been really
popular and kind of a driver of of
upsell and that was
>> that was really an experiment right it
was in a bucket of features that we
tested out I think we had done some
surveys and that one surveyed But I
didn't really necessarily intuitively
believe that it was going to be a winner
feature for us. And so you don't always
know.
>> Yeah. So how do you think about in these
in these experimentation from pricing to
pay walls to onboarding?
What are your kind of northstar metrics
and how do those shift either even
experiment by experiment or year by
year? Uh I you know you mentioned
earlier you do have a lot of churn from
the people who just like uh Facebook
marketplace I just need it for this
weekend. and I'm going to sell five
things on Facebook Marketplace and then
they turn out. So, so how do you how do
you balance? I mean, it must be a really
tricky thing to try and run an
experiment that can generate more
revenue on the payw wall but then lead
to lower retention and getting the wrong
people through the door with the wrong
incentives with the wrong price. So, it
I mean it's such a balancing act. How do
you think about that? I think, you know,
if you look at it from the framework of
the LTV of a cohort, that's probably the
right framework as as a starting point.
And and and it's it's interesting
because that's a hard thing to optimize
for in a single experiment, right? You
know, you have to ultimately kind of
think about how you segment customers
coming through. And so you might, you
know, we have a lot of tools to do that
now, right? So for example, our highest
value customers, we ultimately want to
be both in the premium tier and to be
longer retaining, right? So if we have a
shorter retaining customer
at too high a price, you know, maybe we
haven't done that right. So we're we're
kind of maybe optimizing the premium
subscription differently than we than we
want to optimize a user who's coming in
with lower intent or just wants to get a
quick hit. But but a key thing that that
is really interesting about our product
and this has been true since early on
and the thing you don't want to do I
guess is like try to solve a problem
that's sort of good enough for everyone
but great for no one.
>> Right.
>> Right. And so um there is a set of users
who just kind of wants to get in and out
and there's a different set of users
that you know needs a number for a long
period of time and you know is going to
be price sensitive in a different way.
you know, how much they're going to be
thinking about how much it costs them
per year,
>> right?
>> Whereas you were talking about, you
know, paid downloads, people are
thinking about that as a one-time,
>> right,
>> expense, right?
>> So, balancing those things really cohort
LTV is probably the true north, but
within that, you know, you can you can't
wait for those uh metrics to mature. Um,
so you have to kind of project based on
things that are happening at day eight
or day 30. You know, we have a a
three-day trial. We have a 7-day trial
treatment. And so there are different
different things that you will get
bucketed into depending on on which uh
cohort you're in.
>> So with the cohorting, I imagine you're
not just cohorting by time. Are you
cohorting by answers to onboarding
questions? Because it sounds like you're
not just cohorting
um broadly, but you're trying to find
and you and I have talked about this
before, Eric Crowley, the tourist versus
locals. Yeah. Uh for those of you on
listening to the podcast, if you haven't
heard that episode, go back and find it
because it's really great. But the idea
of like the tourists would be your
Facebook people who are just going to be
there for a week when they, you know,
need to sell a bunch of stuff on
Facebook Marketplace. But what you're
really trying to find is those locals
who are going to be around for a long
time and live there and stay in your
product. But so it sounds like you're
you're actually cohorting by those kind
of intents where you have like a a
tourist cohort and a local cohort and
you're and then you're you're presenting
different pay walls and different
options and different pricing based on
that. Is that is that what I'm hearing?
>> Well, I would say to date we've mostly
done that by presenting different SKUs
and different bundles and letting people
self- select. Um I do think the the more
sophisticated approach is to understand
to try to anticipate who they are in
advance, right? But um there's a
phenomenon first of all you know the
intelligence is getting better and the
tools are getting better to identify
them. Um and then we also have a lot of
users that do that tourist experience
and then come back later. So, we have, I
think, an unusually high percentage of,
you know, people who are, let's call
them quote unquote, new subscribers,
>> you know, who incept a subscription, but
they're not firsttime subscribers. So,
>> you've got the smile curve going.
>> Yeah, it's north of 20%. It's, you know,
somewhere between 20 and 30%. And it's a
very large number, right? And so,
>> you know, one way of looking at that is
like that's a user we failed to retain
on their first tourist visit, right? But
also it maybe it's a user that kind of
like in a Google search they had a great
experience they left and they came back
again when they needed it again. And so
um we are you know trying to give those
people good experiences and maybe do an
increasingly good job educating them on
why you know a good example of this is
so at the end of the life cycle of a
burner phone number the user can burn
the number. Right.
>> Right. And so we've increasingly
explored
what to do at that moment. It's really a
fun moment in the app, right? Like, you
know, in the early days, you know, you'd
hit the button and it would do this
match sound and and this kind of flame
visualization and then like people liked
doing it so much that they kept
accidentally burning their numbers, you
know, and was a lot of support volume,
but you know, using that as a way to
say, well, you may be done with this
transaction, but maybe you want a new
number. And so we we do retain a certain
number of people into kind of a second
shot there. Um and you know ultimately
it's about understanding those users,
right?
>> But but what's been crazy
um and you know we're well over 10 years
into this company and there's still like
the expression is you know there's the
juice is worth the squeeze, right?
There's still
these optimizations that have
meaningful. It's not, we're not talking
about like tiny bits of basis point
types of, you know, uh little
optimizations on whether we underline or
what color blue we're using, right? This
is like a meaningful shift of users when
we introduce kind of a new a new plan.
Um we recently tested um the uh the
making the free trial optional instead
of default
>> and um that was a very positive test for
us interestingly um kind of this is a
good example of something that was like
a little bit trendy. there was somebody
out there talking about, you know, radio
buttons at the free trial payw wall
>> and this that it came in the door to our
company through that kind of dialogue in
the app space and the sort of app growth
community.
>> Yeah. We've talked about it on the
podcast. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> But internally we said, well, one of the
reasons there's an authentic reason for
it isn't just a hack, right? It's like
people come in, they want a phone
number, they want our product, and some
people like want to make sure they lock
it in,
>> right? They don't want to lose it,
right? They really want to come. No, no,
no. I don't need a trial. I want to buy
it. And then other people, you know, I'm
not sure. I'm not sure I want to pay for
this, etc. Give them the free trial, you
know, and so let them self- select. And
and that's a lot of the uh the nuance of
that. But it gets more complicated when
we get to, I think, more um robust
features for those users. So
you can separate locals and tourists not
just at the payw wall in the skew but in
in terms of the actual features. So an
example of something that's in our
premium bundle I gave one earlier around
the phone number lookup but we also have
like an AI voicemail classifier not in
itself a hugely profound feature. Um, we
have some other improvements like um
custom icons and higher quality, you
know, uh, video messaging, things like
this that a tourist wouldn't care about,
>> right?
>> But somebody who's using kind of burner
as their secondary or tertiary phone
number side by side, like with their
home number, they're going to want those
kind of, you know, higher quality
experiences. And so those are bigger
investments from a product point of view
and we don't always know if they'll
drive you know kind of payw wall
conversion immediately. You don't you
don't know on day eight right if that's
a winner experiment and it's it may take
you know real time to build those
features but you'll see it in retention
eventually.
>> Yeah. And then you know one of the
things you and I had talked about on the
retention front is becoming more
multi-product
and potentially even acquiring apps to
drive that retention through bundle and
even the I mean there there's so many
layers to becoming a multi-product
company of solving new needs of bringing
user acquisition in with a different
hook but then has a secondary need. So
how are you thinking about that today?
Yeah, it's it's um absolutely something
we're excited about. So, we've been
thinking about, you know, what our
customer needs are, you know, a lot. And
from a product point of view, we try to
really come from a place of identifying
a problem, validating that problem, and
and solving that problem. Um, but
sometimes those problems are are are
big. We're we're still a relatively
small team. We're about 30 people, and
that's that's healthy, but it's a
complex app. It's mature. there's a lot
to do across you know core and product
and growth and you know um operational
stuff and so um the biggest single
feature we launched that was like a kind
of an expansion of the product portfolio
is in the first quarter of 2025 we
launched a VPN right and VPN is its own
category on the app store you know um
you've you've probably studied that in
detail here and um there's you know kind
of PE stage companies in in the VP PN
space and there's a lot of small ones
and you know um we didn't necessarily
set out to kind of take over that
category so much as to broaden the
offering of burner by by building that
in there's a like-minded customer right
who's concerned about their their
privacy to some degree or you know
looking to hire tools that give them
more control really ultimately over kind
of you know how they're seen how their
identity is understood on the internet
so you can kind of be who you want to be
and be where you want to be with a VPN,
right? Um, so that particular product we
did with a partnership and it's a white
label partnership. There's a provider.
Um, and when when we were able to
integrate that, it was still a pretty
significant investment for us.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and we had to make that investment
without it wasn't easy to validate that
need. So, it kind of ended up being an
expensive investment.
>> Yeah. It's driven a lot of value and
growth of our premium
um tier of our premium skew but it it is
a for us it represents like an example
of a buy build partner type of portfolio
approach right so we decided to partner
>> in that particular case and and it was
>> the build aspects of even in a partner
strategy were still expensive right but
if we had um decided to go become a VPN
company um and build that from scratch
and you know build all the expertise
necessary for that and and by the way
that that product exists in the burner
app and there's a desktop version of it
on on uh Mac and Windows right so it's
kind of a 360 product um you know it's
an expensive investment
>> yeah what what was the decision though
to build it into the product versus
making a second product and and bundling
it
>> as a second app Yeah.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, we've tried that. That's
a tactic that has not worked as well for
us is having multiple apps. So, we have
>> Ad Hoc Labs is is the the parent
company, you know, we have Burner. It's
it's kind of our flagship app, but we
also launched an app called Firewall um
and an app called Dialed to respectively
um do robocall blocking and um business
phone numbers. Um and ne neither one of
those has worked at scale for us. And
I'll just be honest, you know, it's um
these are things that were, you know,
very thoughtful, very, you know, kind of
intentional builds. We did all the
launch things and all the hardening and
and and quite expensive
>> to build apps from scratch.
>> Um and neither of them got real traction
in the app store. Maybe coming back to
that distribution comment earlier. Um
but also in you know over a period of
time we realized you know that the the
acquisition funnel of burner itself in
part because of our strong organic
that's built in and the brand name and
in part because of our mature UA program
we have you know several million people
per year downloading uh burner right and
plenty of those people could use a VPN
>> right
>> and those people are a lot easier to
sort get an offer in front of than to go
construct a new audience through
whatever combination of organic and
attention and paid that we would have to
do even if we cross-promoted. Here's
this other app.
>> Yeah, I know. It's a really good point.
Yeah. Yeah. because and you know I would
think well and that I mean the app store
is a hard place to get distribution
period and so you you would think in one
hand oh launching a VPN app people are
going to searchVPN people are going to
find VPN it's a VPN app so they find
that it's a solution to their problem
for VPN but like that's a whole that's a
whole another company right
>> yeah well when we launched firewall we
learned that lesson really fast and that
was before we got Sherlock when when
Apple launched
>> uh you know kind
you know, screen unknown callers
basically killed that app. Um, and we
didn't even get to Android on that,
which you know, you know, all of our
products are roughly a parody on on iOS
and Android, you know, by by philosophy
when so we can serve our customers and
increasingly on the web, by the way.
>> Um, but that one never made it past that
stage. But, you know, it is
>> it's like you said really hard to launch
apps today.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, I mean, anyone could do it. It's
cheap. It's just very difficult to get
visibility and traction and certainly um
to ASO your way to glory. Yeah. Is a
very difficult thing today.
>> Yeah.
>> Um except maybe if there's a brand new
category. I mean there have been
>> right
>> you know not just the the top LLM sort
of open AI type brands but any number of
AI apps is an example of a category
that's that's done very well as a sort
of new native category.
>> Yeah. Um, but I think in a in a highly
contested category, we're we're used to
being the incumbents burner and and you
know, there's some things that are great
about that, right? And there are some
things that are bummers about that,
right? Like everyone else can target our
keyword and cannibalize the organic
searches for burner
>> that we think are rightfully ours,
right? But we were on the other end of
that when we were trying to compete with
Robociller and whoever else on on
Robocall Block. And um it what is
working so well for us by comparison to
that is saying well we have this robust
funnel we have this user coming in with
high intent that user might be a tourist
that user might be somebody who's like
here for whatever you got.
>> Yeah. um but where we can say great come
for the number maybe add the text
blocking while you're here or maybe you
know maybe you like this AI voicemail
feature and have you ever tried a VPN
you know and you can really broaden
>> the offering there and so we you know
our vision is much broader than being
>> you know private phone numbers right
it's really to help users take control
of their mobile identity and and
communications
>> and so these are tools with which they
can do that So then how you you
mentioned build partner buy. So we've
talked about the build and that's a
struggle launching a a brand new app in
a new category and a huge investment and
everything. The build and partner sounds
like it's it's it's been a nice value ad
to the existing app. U but I know you're
you're starting to consider buying as
well. What does that look like and what
are how are you thinking about that?
>> So first of all, you know, the
underlying goal there is is speed,
right? So it's it's you know how quickly
can you build things or validate and
then build things or partner in things
and and you know how how much can you
drive growth as you get bigger and
bigger right as well as deliver complex
features to users more quickly right
it's like if you have the idea to do
something you know our customers would
love it yesterday right um so yeah we've
been in a certain number of
conversations to acquire apps there's
sort of a I think I mentioned it earlier
you know a little bit of a um kind of I
don't want to call it a death zone, but
it's it's a it's a tough sledding
>> range where you know you've got some
traction and you've got some revenue and
maybe you even have you know cash flow
to fund a certain amount of growth.
>> Um but it, you know, where do you go
from there other than grind,
>> right?
>> Right.
>> We survived it. We got through you know
any number of years that you know we had
a very small team. and we had to figure
it out and kind of no UA specialist on
the team, but we had to do UA or or what
have you. Um or you know the stage where
you have kind of one iOS developer and
that person, you know, takes a vacation
and the whole thing shuts down. And so
um uh we are very keen to grow, you
know, in a very tight way, right? like
we're not we're not interested in kind
of just randomly acquiring other apps,
>> but um we are having a certain number of
conversations right now about things
that would be I think you know very
organic to the burner brand,
>> right?
>> And and if you think about it, it is a
you know the the need that people have
for greater control of their
communications and privacy extends way
beyond phone numbers, right? there's
kind of any number of things that I
think are are good fits for that. So,
yeah, we're excited to be looking at
that. Um, and we're we're I think good
at a bunch of things, right? So, you
know, we've we've had to develop kind of
real subject matter expertise in a bunch
of stages of, you know, funnel
optimization, analytics, and and cohort
math and pricing and and can really
leverage, you know, I it's not massive
consumer scale, but we have a lot of
users with a kind of fairly consistent
>> set of needs that we think we could uh
add some more um meaningful products to.
And so, yeah, we'd love to
>> do that if we can.
>> Cool. Yeah, I'm excited to see where
where this goes. And I mean, I guess
you're you're thinking in those contexts
both where it would be a standalone app
if that app already had some level of
traction, but then also potentially buy
an app where it would then become a
feature in burner. It would just depend
on the the fit and how it would fit into
the product and stuff.
>> Yeah, I think that's right. I mean, not
not all apps that are kind of adjacent
to Burner would lend themselves to being
features inside of the Burner app. I
think some would. I think some would
would benefit from being a standalone,
but the ideal, and we've definitely
given thought to this, would be both,
>> right? So something that has kind of
found some traction, we could absolutely
accelerate the reach and the development
of that app and it could still continue
to be a standalone app that's
complimentary to burner as well. So you
know I you know it's hard to generalize
that because you know every category
we've looked at has been a little bit
different.
>> Yeah.
>> Um but there's some there's some pretty
exciting categories out there.
>> Um and I think some emerging ones that
are that are just emerging needs. Um I
mean an example just by the way and this
is not not to sort of telegraph anything
right but like you know in the world of
AI
you know what does it mean to have
control over your data
>> right
>> that that means something different than
the preai days when you were focused on
maybe Google right and so you know kind
of what's the uh facial recognition mask
right [laughter]
for for something, you know, when you
want to put your your medical labs
numbers into an LLM and and get some
feedback on something like that without
giving Sam Alman your, you know,
personal biometrics, right?
>> This is a a very interesting contrast to
a lot of the buyers in the market today
are the rollups or just buying a bunch
of apps or, you know, I had Blue Throne
on the podcast. They're not just buying
a bunch of apps anymore. They're buying
individual apps, but the whole idea
there is like individual apps that kind
of scale as their own businesses and a
portfolio of like businesses,
>> but this is like a really different
opportunity. So, I'll I'll do the pitch
for you that if you're in the space and
you think um your app would be
meaningful to the burner audience and to
the burner burner brand, his number will
be in the show notes. text Greg
[laughter]
an idea and and pitch him on why he
should buy your app.
>> Awesome. I mean, yeah, I couldn't have
said it better. Thank you. Yeah. Um,
>> but yeah, I mean, I'm not bullish on,
you know, app farms, right? And I think
that by and large has not been validated
by the market. It makes sense why people
thought it was a good idea and so, you
know, some very smart people were were
operating in that in that strategy. But
I think I wouldn't want to own, you
know, 10 $1 million apps.
>> Yeah.
>> Right. I just don't think there's that
much leverage in trying to scale things
that don't
>> Yeah.
>> connect to one another, right? Um
whereas
having multiple multi-million dollar
apps that are complimentary to one
another, there there are it's it's much
easier for us to add 5 million in
revenue to our app than it would be to
take 500k app and turn into a $5 million
app.
>> Yeah. Yeah. If you're uh if you're
trying to pump and dump, Greg is a very
sophisticated buyer, [laughter] that's
not going to work out. But it makes
sense. You're kind of looking for the
sleep stories to the calm. Like you're
looking for secondary product market fit
to build out this and and so almost and
that's right as you did with the VPN.
It's not even multi-product necessarily,
but it's multi-solution for the audience
that you already have.
>> Well, that's the starting point. So
that's actually a really interesting
dimension of it, right? So, if you take,
you know, several million burner users
coming in a year and then you crossell
them, let's say VPN,
that's terrific. But what about when you
can then with that combined product,
let's say there's another component of
it, reach an even bigger audience,
combined offering, right? And
>> to the degree that
>> the retention math really drives that,
right? where you know a user that comes
in
uh you know I I I use this example of of
GoDaddy a lot like it's kind of an
antiquated brand and whatever but they
you know they kind of you know you come
for the domain and you end up with a
website and email and
>> you know e-commerce and you know
suddenly you're like a 84x LTV
>> customer for them and and that that
magic of bundling is not
>> it's not new
>> right people have been doing it a long
time in cable and telecom subscriptions
Um but it is um you know tricky
sometimes to apply and it's a real
opportunity area within within I think
consumer mobile subscription generally.
I think if you're not thinking about
bundling, you should be, right? And I
think that's where a lot of opportunity
unlock for us is both like you said
within the current sort of scale of the
funnel and then in expanding the reach,
you know, maybe with a higher CAC
target, right, and a broader bigger
budget, right, to a to a broader
audience. So we are working on some
internal build stuff and some partner
stuff that I think expands the strike
zone of what burner is as well.
>> Yeah. And I think that's a great way
folks should be thinking about it too
about that secondary and tertiary
product market fit and how to how to
build it out into this broader offering
when you have found product market fit
in that single thing and you're growing
and you're doing well. But then that
does provide more opportunity, an
opportunity to grow faster, opportunity
to increase that LTV across that cohort.
So yeah, uh fascinating new direction
for for burner and an opportunity I
think a lot of people should be
considering over the years. I think it's
a great place to wrap up the
conversation. I've started doing this
lightning round and funny enough, I beta
tested this lightning round with you and
a few other founders uh on a rooftop in
LA. It was an incredible evening.
There's there's pictures on the
internet, but we purposely didn't record
it. This one will be recorded. So, uh I
don't know if you're going to select
different answers. Um but it was it was
so much fun. We did this live. Um there
were about 20 25 people in attendance.
There were I think four founders sitting
there and and and I hosted a panel and
it was so much fun. Uh and so I started
doing this uh in the podcast now to ask
these three questions. The first one is
what is the biggest we'll start with the
fail. What's the biggest fail of the
past year? Experiments, product launch,
um, hiring. I mean, just what's the
biggest fail of the year?
>> Yeah, it just by the way that that panel
was great and it's a testament to the
community being, you know, really coming
together here. Um, which which I really
enjoyed. Um so the biggest fail in the
past year is the same one that we really
have every year which is one way or
another is you know building things too
expensively and that take too long
>> that aren't always the right thing
>> and kind of ultimately the tax on on
velocity that that incurs because of the
opportunity costs. So in the in the past
year I mentioned we shipped VPN um and
that is an example of something that you
know while it's working well as a
product we built it in a very expensive
way
>> um even with a partner in the mix right
and so if we could run that again we
might have done it in a in a more nimble
way
>> um and I mean I feel like we learned
that same lesson with audio messaging
and learn that lesson with you know kind
of
>> infinite numbers of features going back
it's a tough balance to strike because
you you you want to put your best foot
forward and like build the best possible
product and so it's just so easy to
overinvest when when you're passionate
about something and you're confident it
you're somewhat confident it's going to
work and it's working but yeah
>> well I think that's especially true in a
in aoriented team my co-founder is this
product he's a design you know we have
you know passionate members of the teams
throughout engineers and and they want
to build things the right way right So
that's an important differentiation. I
know this is supposed to be the
lightning round, but
>> I know I was going to [laughter] say
that
>> that's an important differentiation
between just like let's, you know,
analyze our way to a growth hack, right?
It's like it's a meaningful feature.
>> Yeah. Well, we've already blown up the
lightning round. So, how would you coach
yourself and how are you coaching the
team to think about in 2026
>> um being able to take those swings but
not spend so much at every at bat?
I think the right way to think about it
is probably there are no sort of
medium-siz at bats, right? You you
either do something that's kind of a
painted door test, which is something I
know you've talked about a lot, or maybe
using, you know, kind of an inapp modal
or something in the onboarding funnel or
you rebuild the whole onboarding funnel
and it's going to take however many
sprints it takes. Um, but it's very hard
to do kind of this one surgical thing
that involves a complex system and not
have it turn into complexity that that
sort of spirals. And so that's a big
learning and it's one in our um sort of
product road mapping and engineering
kind of road mapping process we're
trying to get, you know, ever tighter
about.
>> Yeah. All right. What was your biggest
win of the past year? biggest win of the
past year, I mean, aside from launching
premium full stop, was definitely adding
technology to increase our uh payw wall
testing speed.
>> Yeah.
>> Um we um were always a very test-driven
company. Um but we were, you know,
shipping one or two payw wall tests a
month and we're we're able to do, you
know, a multiple of that today. And it's
it's very interesting because it pulled
all the you know kind of the velocity is
now you know on the product team not not
gated by the engineering
>> right
>> team and probably the speed to results
is mostly gated by analytics now and
maturing of data as opposed to how fast
can we ship features. Yeah,
>> it's or excuse me, tests, but it's still
true that we don't always know the ones
that are going to win. Like, you know,
there's kind of one winner for every
four or five that we do.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Payroll velocity. That's uh
it's been a big topic over the last
couple years. And I I there's legs
there. I mean, we've see a lot of apps
do really well that that you just
wouldn't think that moment would have as
big of impact as it does, but it does.
>> That first hour of the user journey is
just incredibly important. I just feel
like I've heard that again and again.
and not just the pay wall.
>> We want to expand that into onboarding
and and even sort of win back, you know,
kind of cancellation flows, things like
that.
>> All right, last question.
Growth would be easier if
>> if my users would stick around longer,
>> especially those tourists. Yeah, it's a
hard balancing act. Attention versus,
you know, kind of optimization at the
payw wall and uh one we'll probably talk
about the next time we get together,
David. So,
>> why why specifically though? Uh, I mean,
you know, the math works out as far as
like anybody who sticks around a little
longer. You can spend more money on
them, the money you spent this year
becomes free cash flow next year that
you can invest in more user acquisition.
But are there specific things you think
when you say growth would be easier if
retention were better?
>> Let me put it this way. If if I were
advising someone on how to build a
large-scale subscription business, I
would probably advise them not to start
with a product that's inherently
temporary.
>> Right.
>> Right. So burner is very churn biased by
its nature as a
>> by it
>> throwaway phone number and people love
to burn the numbers you know um so you
know all jokes aside I think we've done
a good job of evolving it toward a a um
kind of a subscription retention
business but that's almost by kind of
the survivor bias and of the relatively
smaller percentage of customers who stay
a really long time.
>> Yeah, that's fascinating. All right,
well this is so much fun. Thank you so
much for joining me. really appreciate
it. Um, we've already kind of pitched,
but anything else? Are you hiring or
anything other than um, people uh,
pitching you an app that you wanted to
share as we wrap up?
>> Yeah, thank you for saying that and
thanks for a great conversation. We have
a couple of very interesting roles open
um, in both product and analytics and
engineering at the moment and so I would
love to hear from anyone who might be
interested and I and I also really
welcome hearing from founders in the
space. I'm kind of in touch with lots of
people. Well, my door is always open and
love to be helpful. If if I can save you
some some some hard years in there in
the middle, I' I'd love to be of help.
>> That's awesome. And and as we said
earlier, Greg's phone number, his
burner, but his phone number [laughter]
will be in. So, uh text him. I I would
imagine you'd prefer a text first. Uh
>> a text would be good. Uh but it will be
really me at the other end of it.
>> Yeah. Awesome. All right. Thanks so
much.
>> Thanks, David.
Thanks [music] so much for listening. If
you have a minute, please leave a review
in your favorite podcast player. You can
also stop by chat.subclub.com
to join our private community.
[music]